# **VINOD SANTHARAM**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **DETAILS**

#### **ADDRESS**

Bangkok, Thailand

### **PHONE**

+66970082783

#### **EMAIL**

vinod.santharam@gmail.com

#### NATIONALITY

French

#### SKILLS

Front-end

UI/UX

React

React Native

Angular

TypeScript

.NET Core

#### LINKS



linkedin.com/in/vinodsantharam



github.com/vinodsantharam

#### **PROFILE**

I am a graduate of a Master's program in computer science, with work experience as a software developer engineer and UI architect, where I proved my excellent communication skills and my leadership. I am passionate about new technology and have intellectual curiosity.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## Software Engineer, 2c2p (Ant Group)

Bangkok, Thailand

July 2024 — Today

- Taking a leadership role in the development of Angular web applications
- Worked in collaboration with System Analyst to design new screens
- Presented E2E Automated tests with Gherkin/Cucumber.js
- Designed and implemented P.O.C. agent with OpenAl Agents SDK

#### **Software Engineer, Liveblocks**

Remote

May 2022 — Dec 2022

- Developed **React Native** open source example showcasing **Liveblocks** integration
- $\bullet\,$  Designed and implemented customer REST APIs using node.js
- Constructed foundational elements for open source starter kit (next.js)

## **Software Engineer, Nexus Innovations Inc.**

Montréal, Canada

May 2020 - Apr 2022

- Taking a leadership role in the development of Angular web applications
- Designed and programmed UI Kit & custom components using **React.js** and **MUI** library, making them accessible to the design team on **Storybook**
- Conducted training sessions for junior developers on Angular & React.js
- Organized and animated a workshop about RxJS

## UI Architect, nag informatik ag

Basel, Switzerland

Apr 2017 - Aug 2019

- Collaborated as a UI/UX Designer using Figma
- Directed the front-end architecture, providing coding guidance and design patterns
- Led the development of Angular and Vue.js web applications
- Instructed junior developers in React.js, Vue.js, Angular, CSS, and RxJS
- Organized workshops on **Ethereum** blockchain
- Presented bi-monthly company speeches on UI/UX and blockchain technology

## LANGUAGES

French

. . . . .

English

. . . . .

German

• • • 0 0

Tamil

. . . . .

Japanese

• 0 0 0 0

Thai

• 0 0 0 0

#### HOBBIES

Cooking

Traveling

Reading

Video Games

Muay Thai

Football

Table Tennis

Running

## REFERENCES

#### **GUILLAUME SALLES**

Ex CTO at Liveblocks

guillaume.salles@me.com

#### SÉBASTIEN HEMOND

Ex COO at HalfSerious

sebastien.hemond@gmail.com

#### **CHRISTOPHE HETZEL**

Executive board at nag ag informatik christophe.hetzel@nag.ch

## Software Engineer, WorkLeap (ex GSOFT Inc.)

Apr 2016 - Nov 2016

- Evaluated and improved code design/architecture
- Developed custom controls in WPF through Microsoft Blend
- Authored comprehensive front-end XAML/MVVM coding guidance
- Provided training for junior developers in WPF
- Participated in the redesign of UI/UX in collaboration with business analysts and designers
- Recognized as the best monthly department employee for outstanding contributions

#### Software Engineer, Orckestra Inc.

Montréal, Canada

Apr 2013 - Apr 2016

- Engaged in back-end and front-end development following Scrum & Lean Agile methodologies
- Utilized Reactive Extensions (Rx) with C#
- Facilitated knowledge transfer within the team for front-end technologies
- Contributed to enhancing the front-end architecture
- Authored integration tests using Specflow
- Led the POS (Point Of Sale) project (Universal Windows), overseeing technical decisions, fullstack development, analysis, design, and code review
- Actively participated in UI/UX processes

#### **EDUCATION**

## Master of Science, University of Strasbourg

Strasbourg, France

Sep 2009 — Sep 2011

Software Engineering, Algorithms, Bioinformatics, Network, Semantics

## **Bachelor of Science, University of Strasbourg**

Strasbourg, France

Sep 2005 — Sep 2009

Software Engineering, Database, Data Structures, Mathematics

## PERSONAL PROJECT

## **CTO & Principle Software Engineer, Di Vini**

Remote

Oct 2020 - Dec 2021

Di Vini aims to create and store tasting notes for wines. Developed using **React Native**, the app is accessible on both the App Store and Play Store.

- Set up the development environment, including VS Code, libraries, and file structure
- Implemented Google Analytics for analytics tracking
- Integrated **Firebase** for storing wine notes
- Created custom components such as an expander, input, toggle button, ...
- Used Fastlane for package management and release processes

Montréal, Canada